<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Jun Wong</title>
    <link>https://junwong.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jun Wong</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://junwong.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rubbish economics: Decreasing the use of informal dumps in Bengaluru slums</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/research/bangalore/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/research/bangalore/</guid>
      <description>We will study the spatial distribution of waste generation and public waste service provision throughout Bengaluru. This will inform the design of targeted supply- and demand-side interventions intended to expand the reach and quality of waste services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimalist MATLAB Template for Scientific Figures</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/d4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/d4/</guid>
      <description>This template produces scientific figures with MATLAB. The figures have a minimalist design and are customized for academics and other researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimalist LaTeX Template for Academic Papers</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/d2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/d2/</guid>
      <description>This template produces a research paper with LaTeX. The paper has a minimalist design and is customized for academics and scientists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimalist Hugo Template for Academic Websites</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/d5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/d5/</guid>
      <description>This template produces a personal website with Hugo. The website has a minimalist design and is customized for academics, scientists, and researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimalist LaTeX Template for Academic Presentations</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/d1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/d1/</guid>
      <description>This template produces a research presentation with LaTeX and Beamer. The slides have a minimalist design and are customized for academics and scientists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimalist LaTeX Commands to Write Math</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/d3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/d3/</guid>
      <description>This collection of minimalist commands make it easy to write mathematical expressions with LaTeX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Cycles and How to Tame Them</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/c5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/c5/</guid>
      <description>This minicourse describes business cycles, develops a matching model to explain them, and discusses how monetary and fiscal policy can tame them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening up military innovation: An evaluation of reforms to the U.S. Air Force SBIR program</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/research/sbir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/research/sbir/</guid>
      <description>A critical dimension of government innovation procurement is whether to specify desired products (conventional) or allow firms to suggest ideas (open). We evaluate reforms to a U.S. Air Force R&amp;amp;D grant program where both conventional and open competitions were held simultaneously. Open awards increase commercial innovation and technology adoption by the military.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Slack</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/c2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/c2/</guid>
      <description>This graduate course presents matching models of economic slack and uses them to study business-cycle fluctuations, monetary policy, and fiscal policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lender automation and racial disparities in credit access</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/research/ppp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/research/ppp/</guid>
      <description>Process automation can reduce racial disparities in credit access. We study this in the context of the Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) where lenders faced no credit risk but decided which firms to serve. Black-owned firms primarily obtained PPP loans from automated fintech lenders, especially in areas with high racial animus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unemployment</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/c1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/c1/</guid>
      <description>This graduate course presents matching models of unemployment and uses them to study unemployment fluctuations, job rationing, and labor market policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market potential for CO2 removal and sequestration from renewable natural gas production in California</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/research/rng/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/research/rng/</guid>
      <description>We develop a spatially explicit optimization model to assess niche markets for renewable natural gas (RNG) production with carbon capture and sequestration (CCS) from waste biomass in California. Policy incentives can catalyze niche markets for the production of renewable natural gas with carbon capture and sequestration from waste biomass in California.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovative wood use can enable carbon-beneficial forest management in California</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/papers/wooduse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/papers/wooduse/</guid>
      <description>Natural carbon sinks can help mitigate climate change but are exposed to wildfire risk. Forest management can reduce wildfire risk but incur carbon losses because wood residues are often burnt or left to decay. We assess climate change mitigation potential and wildfire outcomes across forest management scenarios and several wood products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermediate Macroeconomics</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/c4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/c4/</guid>
      <description>This undergraduate course covers IS-LM model of business cycles, matching model of unemployment, inflation, and Malthusian and Solowian models of growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematics for Macroeconomics</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/c3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/c3/</guid>
      <description>This graduate course covers basic mathematical methods for macroeconomics: dynamic programming, optimal control, and differential equations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Location</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/location/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/location/</guid>
      <description>My mailing and office addresses at the University of California, Santa Cruz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Hours</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/officehours/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/officehours/</guid>
      <description>Schedule and location for my office hours at the University of California, Santa Cruz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://junwong.org/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://junwong.org/research/</guid>
      <description>Working Papers Opening up military innovation: Causal effects of reforms to U.S. defense research with Sabrina Howell, Jason Rathje, and John Van Reenen Reject and Resubmit, Journal of Political Economy Ungated Publications Lender automation and racial disparities in credit access with Sabrina Howell, Theresa Kuchler, David Snitkof, and Johannes Stroebel The Journal of Finance (2024) Ungated Market potential for CO2 removal and sequestration from renewable natural gas production in California with Daniel Sanchez, Jonathan Santoso, and Marjorie Went Environmental Science and Technology (2022) Ungated Innovative wood use can enable carbon-beneficial forest management in California with Bodie Cabiyo, Brandon Collins, Jeremy Fried, William Steward, and Daniel Sanchez Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences (2021) Ungated Selected Works in Progress Subsidies in the presence of informality with Zachary Kuloszewski</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
